<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Tweets>
  <Tweet>
    How to Create an <a href="http://t.co/rbcmvBwL" /> Wizard Interface in <a href="http://t.co/rbcmvBwL" /> MVC &amp; WebForms: Check out this slic... <a href="http://t.co/E5n9xeTy">http://t.co/E5n9xeTy</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    Extending condolences and prayers from all of us at DevExpress to the friends and family of Victor Gaudioso. His... <a href="http://t.co/XeQO1w23">http://t.co/XeQO1w23</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    Endless Pagination - Load content using DevExpress <a href="http://t.co/rbcmvBwL">http://t.co/rbcmvBwL</a> while scrolling: Check out this solution ... <a href="http://t.co/0O6qPwzc">http://t.co/0O6qPwzc</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    I posted 18 photos on Facebook in the album "DevExpress @ DevConnections" <a href="http://t.co/5xMThq3p">http://t.co/5xMThq3p</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    Reporting from DevConnections: Tooling is the new frontier: This week we were at DevConnections in Las Vegas. It... <a href="http://t.co/7BNFcczR">http://t.co/7BNFcczR</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    I posted a new photo to Facebook <a href="http://t.co/DnWlbuF9">http://t.co/DnWlbuF9</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    DevExpress at DevConnections: it must be good, it’s got Dev in the title: Just a quick note to say that the team... <a href="http://t.co/YTwupydu">http://t.co/YTwupydu</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    Come to "Visual Studio 11 Beta Celebration" Tuesday, March 27 from 7:00 pm to 10:00 pm. <a href="http://t.co/26Mhw1Ke">http://t.co/26Mhw1Ke</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    Using RAD Studio XE2 Update 4? Make sure you get VCL subscription 11.2.5!: A couple of weeks ago we released 11.... <a href="http://t.co/ZjAxOpra">http://t.co/ZjAxOpra</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    Have you registered for <a href="http://twitter.com/MehulHarry">@MehulHarry</a>'s DevExpress webcast in conjunction w/<a href="http://twitter.com/MSDN">@MSDN</a> on 19-March? Register your place here <a href="http://t.co/O78TD4KZ">http://t.co/O78TD4KZ</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    Case Study: Building the Workflow-Based Licensing Application with XAF: Check out a case study from Nathaniel La... <a href="http://t.co/UICqkKLJ">http://t.co/UICqkKLJ</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    Webinar Video: Pivot and Analyze Data in your <a href="http://t.co/rbcmvBwL">http://t.co/rbcmvBwL</a> MVC Razor Websites: Check out this video for t... <a href="http://t.co/qD9YXmmh">http://t.co/qD9YXmmh</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    CodeMash / Michigan Tour Recap: Mehul and I had a great time at this year's Codemash conference held in Sandusky... <a href="http://t.co/9jx0aoGS">http://t.co/9jx0aoGS</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    DXperience and the Visual Studio 11 beta: I’m sure that you have all heard by now that Microsoft have published ... <a href="http://t.co/ubYqzJlf">http://t.co/ubYqzJlf</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    VCL Subscription 11.2.4 released!: Just a quick note to all our VCL customers: we’ve just released the v2011.2.4... <a href="http://t.co/CYQdn0Ak">http://t.co/CYQdn0Ak</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    Mmm, news about Visual Studio 11 and .NET 4.5 beta!: After some four or five months of radio silence from DevDiv... <a href="http://t.co/UXelRl0R">http://t.co/UXelRl0R</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    BASTA Spring and DevExpress Day in Germany!: Today I will be leaving for Germany to attend BASTA spring as well ... <a href="http://t.co/xdNWJEo3">http://t.co/xdNWJEo3</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    Oliver Sturm's Free DevExpress Day - Bad Ems, Germany: Join Oliver Sturm in Bad Ems, Germany for a full day of D... <a href="http://t.co/JmdErZhW">http://t.co/JmdErZhW</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    Healthcare Information Technology (HIMformatics) - a visually stunning DevExpress-enabled <a href="http://t.co/rbcmvBwL">http://t.co/rbcmvBwL</a> we... <a href="http://t.co/a4JkMLbq">http://t.co/a4JkMLbq</a>
  </Tweet>
  <Tweet>
    <a href="http://t.co/rbcmvBwL">http://t.co/rbcmvBwL</a> HTML Editor - Keyboard Shortcuts: Keyboard shortcuts are great. Especially when you're writi... <a href="http://t.co/lcqMM1uA">http://t.co/lcqMM1uA</a>
  </Tweet>
</Tweets>
